所以我们看了名单和日期
So we've looked at lists and dates
作为可变对象的示例。
as examples of mutable objects.
我们要看的下一个可变对象
The next mutable object we're going to look at
是迭代器。
is an iterator.
迭代器是一个
An iterator is an object that steps
通过元素集合并返回
through a collection of elements and returns each
一个接一个。
of those elements one by one.
迭代器在Java中自动在后台使用
Iterators are automatically used behind the scenes in Java
当你使用for循环时
when you're using a for loop to step
通过列表或数组。
through a list or an array.
所以如果你有一个列表并且你写了一个for循环
So if you have a list and you write a for loop that
说你要严格--你要看
says you want strict-- you want to look
在该列表的每个元素上，Java编译器实际上
at each element of that list, then the Java compiler actually
把它改写成某种
rewrites that into something kind
，通过调用
of like this-- creates an iterator object by calling
列表中返回
a method on the list that returns
迭代器类型的新对象。
a new object of type iterator.
然后循环重复调用
And then the loop repeatedly calls
下一步要找出迭代器是否已经结束。
has next to find out if the iterator has gotten to the end.
如果没有，它会问迭代器--
And if it hasn't, it asks the iterator--
调用迭代器next方法以获取下一个元素
calls the iterators next method to get the next element
从名单上。
from that list.
所以这条线变成了这三条线。
So this line here turns into these three lines here.
这里有一个迭代器，它是一个可变的对象
And there's this iterator, which is a mutable object, that
基本上表示通过列表移动的位置
basically represents a position through the list moving
通过列表。
through the list.
关于迭代器的两个重要方法--
And two important methods on an iterator--
next返回集合中的下一个元素
next returns the next element in the collection
并向前移动指针。
and advances the pointer.
接下来的测试你是否
And has next tests whether you've
是不是到了收藏的最后。
gotten to the end of the collection or not.
所以下一个方法实际上是一个变异器。
So this next method is actually a mutator.
它改变了迭代器的含义。
It changes what the iterator means.
它改变了它的价值。
It changes its value.
它改变了“下一个”和“下一个”将在
It changes what has next and next will return when
你下次再打给他们。
you call them another time.
为了更好地理解迭代器的工作原理，
So to better understand how an iterator works,
下面是一个迭代器的简单实现，它只起作用
here's a simple implementation of an iterator that only works
在字符串的数组列表上。
on array lists of strings.
我们一般不想使用MyIterator。
We don't want to use MyIterator in general.
实际上，您需要使用数组列表自己的迭代器
You actually want to use the array list's own iterator
反对。
object.
但我们写这篇文章是为了——为了理解
But we're writing this for the sake of-- for understanding how
这是一个简单的例子。
it works on a simple example.
所以这使用了一些Java语言特性
So this uses a few Java language features that maybe you haven't
在这一点上看到了很多。
seen much up to this point.
所以我们要简单地解释一下。
So we're going to explain them very briefly.
实例变量，也称为字段，
Instance variables, which are also called fields,
是与每个实例关联的变量，
are variables that are associated with each instance,
类的每个对象值。
each object value of a class.
所以MyIterator对象将有两个实例变量
So a MyIterator object is going to have two instance variables
其中有一个列表和一个索引。
in it-- a list and an index.
所以这个列表指向字符串列表
So this list points to the list of strings
我们实际上在重复。
that we're actually iterating over.
迭代器需要保持这种状态。
The iterator needs to hold on to that.
index是当前值，列表中的当前索引，
And index is the current value, the current index in that list,
迭代器当前正在返回的。
that the iterator is currently returning.
下一步是推进这一进程。
And next is going to advance that.
下一个要测试的是
And has next is going to test whether that's
在名单的最后。
at the end of the list.
这里还有一个构造函数。
There's also a constructor here.
构造函数是一种特殊的方法
And a constructor is a special kind of method
这将生成类的新值、新实例。
that makes a new value, a new instance, of the class.
您应该已经在Python中看到了构造函数
You should have seen constructors already in Python
也。
as well.
这个会拿走我们想要的名单
This one will take the list that we want
作为参数迭代。
to iterate over as a parameter.
它坚持住了。
And it holds on to that.
它将其存储在实例变量中。
It stores it in the instance variable.
你注意到我们在这里使用的是this关键字。
And you notice that we're using here the this keyword.
这实际上是Python中self关键字的Java版本。
This is actually Java's version of the self keyword in Python.
Java的一个特性是
One of the features of Java though-- you
从Python可以知道
may know from Python that self normally
必须作为参数之一传递
has to be passed as one of the arguments
进入构造函数或实例方法。
into a constructor or an instance method.
在Java中，这是隐式的。
In Java, this is implicit.
你知道你能用它的方式
And the way that you know that you are able to use it
构造函数和实例方法不
is that a constructor and instance method does not
这里有静电。
have static here.
所以没有静态意味着你可以访问
So the absence of static means that you have access
对这个物体。
to a this object.
你可以用这个来指代它
And you can use this to refer to it
尤其是访问列表和索引等字段。
and particularly to access its fields like list and index.
这就是这里发生的事。
And that's what's happening here.
所以这是一个构造器。
So that's a constructor.
这是一个实例方法。
Well, here's one of the instance methods.
记住，迭代器中需要两个。
Remember, we need two in an iterator.
我们需要下一个测试我们是否在最后
We need has next to test whether we're at the end
然后返回下一个值。
and next that returns the next value.
再说一遍，我们知道这些是实例方法，因为它们
And again, we know these are instance methods because they
不要有静电。
don't have a static.
必须在迭代器的一个实例上调用它们
They will have to be called on an instance of the my iterator
上课。
class.
当你在这个方法里面的时候，它就会变成这个对象。
And that will become this object when you're inside this method.
但现在，注意这个特殊的例子，
But now, notice in this particular case,
我们不用这个。
we're not using this.
我们不是指这个。
We're not referring to this.
Java允许我们简单地隐式地引用字段，
Java allows us to simply refer implicitly to the fields,
对于类的实例变量，如果
to the instance variables, of a class if we're
在实例方法中。
inside an instance method.
所以这个索引实际上是指
So this index is actually referring
到那个实例变量。
to that instance variable.
我们可以把这个点索引写在这里
And we could have written this dot index here
就像我们在这里写的一样。
in the same way we wrote it here.
我们选择不只是为了方便。
We chose not to just for convenience.
您将看到许多Java程序员忽略了这一点。
And you'll see many Java programmers omitting the this.
所以，顺便说一下，我们也有一些不同
So we also have, by the way, some differences
在私人和公共之间。
between private and public.
私人物品，私人类和变量，
Private things, private classes and variables,
只能在类的文本中访问
can only be accessed within the text of the class
他们所属的。
that they belong to.
所以这意味着这个列表和这个索引
So that means that this list and this index
只能从MyIterator中查看和访问
can only be seen and accessed from within this MyIterator
上课。
class.
而公共的，比如构造器
Whereas public ones, like the constructor
像这些方法一样，可以从任何地方调用。
and like these methods, can be called from anywhere.
我们以前也讨论过决赛。
And we've talked about final before.
Final使这个引用，这个列表变量，不可变。
Final makes this reference, this list variable, immutable.
这意味着它只能指向那个列表。
It means that it can only ever point to that list.
特别是，当我们绘制这个快照图时
So in particular, when we draw this snapshot diagram that
显示MyIterator的特定实例及其字段，
shows a particular instance of MyIterator with its fields,
对于它的实例变量，它的列表变量
with its instance variables, its list variable
指向特定数组列表。
points to a particular array list.
那是一个双箭头，因为它是最终的。
And that's a double arrow because it's final.
这意味着这个箭头永远不会改变。
And that means that this arrow can never actually change.
但是请注意，它指向的数组列表对象
But notice that the array list object that it points to
是可变的。
is mutable.
对吗？
Right?
它周围没有双重边界。
It doesn't have a double border around it.
列表通常是可变的。
Lists are, in general, mutable.
所以元素可以在里面改变。
So elements can be changed within it.
声明此列表为final无效
Declaring this list final has no effect
这个对象是可变的还是不可变的。
on whether this object is mutable or immutable.
现在，为什么存在迭代器？
Now, why do iterators exist?
有很多种收集数据
Well, there are many kinds of collection data
结构——链表、映射、哈希表和数组。
structures-- linked lists, maps, and hash tables, and arrays.
他们每个人都有不同的类型
And they each have a different kind
内部代表。
of internal representation.
以及迭代器思想的优势
And advantage of the iterator idea
我们现在有一个统一的方法
is that we now have a single uniform way
要访问它们，一个具有方法next和has next的对象。
to access them all, an object with methods next and has next.
所以客户端代码可以简单得多。
So the client code can be much simpler.
我们可以使用不同的收藏
And we can use various different collections
而不更改使用该集合的代码。
without changing the code that is using that collection.
所以大多数现代语言，包括
So most modern languages, including
Python和C Sharp、Ruby以及Java，
Python and C Sharp and Ruby, as well as Java,
有迭代器的概念。
have the notion of an iterator.
这是一个非常有效的设计模式。
It's a very effective design pattern.
设计模式是经过充分测试的解决方案
A design pattern is a well tested solution
一个共同的问题。
to a common problem.
我们将看到许多其他的设计模式
And we'll see many other design patterns
当我们走完全程。
as we move through the course.